<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">4 Wine Wine</string>
    <string name="edit_message">Enter a message</string>
    <string name="button_send">Send</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_main">MainActivity</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hey there!</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_message">DisplayMessageActivity</string>
    <string name="button_BAC">BAC Checker</string>
    <string name="title_activity_home">BAC</string>
    <string name="bac_title">BAC Checker</string>
    <string name="entry_title">Entry</string>
    <string name="title_activity_bacfinal">BACFinal</string>
    <string name="title_activity_tools">Tools</string>
    <string name="button_tools">Tools</string>
    <string name="intro">An application for all your wine drinking needs!</string>
    <string name="pairings">Food Pairings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_pairings">Pairings</string>
    <string name="location">Winery Locations</string>
    <string name="title_activity_locations">Locations</string>
    <string name="sex">Gender:</string>
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="education">Education</string>
    <string name="title_activity_education">Education</string>
    <string name="title_activity_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="glass">glass</string>
    <string name="Male">Male</string>
    <string name="Female">Female</string>
    <string name="Weight">Weight</string>
    <string name="Num_of_drinks">Number of Drinks</string>
    <string name="Hours_since">Hours Since Drinking</string>
    <string name="calculateBAC">Calculate BAC</string>
    <string name="Education">Education</string>
    <string name="Etiquette">Etiquette</string>
    <string name="Regions">Regions</string>
    <string name="Types">Types</string>
    <string name="Production">Production</string>
    <string name="history">History</string>
    <string name="Pricing">Pricing</string>
    <string name="digitalcellar">Digital Cellar</string>
    <string name="button_WineLibraries">Wine Libraries</string>
    <string name="button_add_a_wine">Add a Wine</string>
    <string name="title_activity_sample">SampleActivity</string>
    <string name="favorites">Favorites</string>
    <string name="wishlist">Wishlist</string>
    <string name="search_wines">Search Wines</string>
    <string name="title_activity_test">TestActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_wine_libraries">Libraries</string>
    <string name="title_activity_digital_cellar">Libraries</string>
    <string name="title_activity_favorites">Favorites</string>
    <string name="title_activity_wishlist">Wishlist</string>
    <string name="title_activity_search_wines">Search</string>
    <string name="tbd">TBD</string>
    <string name="title_activity_pair__meat">Find Wine</string>
    <string name="title_section1">Section 1</string>
    <string name="title_section2">Section 2</string>
    <string name="title_section3">Section 3</string>
    <string name="title_activity_foodtowine_meat">Find Wine</string>
    <string name="beef">Cabernet Sauvignon, Merlot, Malbec, Red Bordeaux, Shiraz, or Zinfandel</string>
    <string name="chicken">Chardonnay or White Burgandy</string>
    <string name="fish">Chardonnay or Sauvignon Blanc</string>
    <string name="pork">Chardonnay, Sauvignon Blanc, or Riesling</string>
    <string name="title_activity_foodtowine_pasta">Find Wine</string>
    <string name="tomato">Chianti, Sangiovese, or Zinfandel</string>
    <string name="cream">Sauvignon Blanc, Chardonnay, or Pinot Grigio</string>
    <string name="green">Chardonnay</string>
    <string name="mush">Pinot Noir</string>
    <string name="bleu">Sauternes or Port</string>
    <string name="hard">Cabernet Sauvignon</string>
    <string name="soft">Chardonnay, Pinot Grigio, Sauvignon Blanc, or Pinot Noir</string>
    <string name="title_activity_foodtowine__veggie">Find Wine</string>
    <string name="title_activity_foodtowine_cheese">Find Wine</string>
    <string name="title_activity_wineto_food">Find Food</string>
    <string name="chardonnay">Poultry and game birds, veal and pork, rabbit fish and pasta preparations which feature cream and/or butter, mushrooms.</string>
    <string name="sauvignon">First courses, seafood, ethnic dishes—pastas, curries, salsas, spicy sausages, vegetable dishes, luncheon salads, olive-oil based dishes, tomato sauces, goat cheese.</string>
    <string name="chenin">Braised Chicken, sushi and other Oriental dishes, poultry, pork.</string>
    <string name="gewur">Spicy cuisines such as Chinese, Mexican, and Indian, mild sausages, fruit salad.</string>
    <string name="riesling">Crabmeat, appetizers and finger foods, pork, salads.</string>
    <string name="cabernet">Beef, lamb, pork, duck, game meats, cheeses.</string>
    <string name="merlot">Beef, lamb, pork, duck, game meats, cheeses, stews, pizza, heart pastas.</string>
    <string name="zinfandel">Hamburgers, beef, lamb, venison and game, hearty pastas, turkey, stews, pizza.</string>
    <string name="pinot">Lamb, duck, turkey, game birds, beef, rabbit, semi-soft cheeses.</string>
    <string name="pink">Best with smoked foods, quiche, pork and ham,Mexican and Thai food. Can be served with all food.</string>
    <string name="brut">Aperitifs and first courses, fruits and nuts. Fuller bodied variations go well with any fish and chicken.</string>
    <string name="blancdenoir">Aperitif, with lunch, desserts.</string>
    <string name="blancdeblanc">Caviar.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_foodto_wine">Find Wine</string>
    <string name="title_activity_winetofood_white">Find Food</string>
    <string name="title_activity_winetofood_red">Find Food</string>
    <string name="title_activity_winetofood_other">Find Food</string>
    <string name="title_activity_my_wines">My Wines</string>
    <string name="title_activity_types_quiz1">Types Quiz</string>
    <string name="title_activity_quiz_result1">Quiz Result</string>
    <string name="title_activity_display_search">Display Search</string>
    <string name="title_activity_view_wine">View Wine</string>
    <string name="title_activity_food_pairings_quiz">Pairings Quiz</string>
    <string name="title_activity_view_fav_wine">Wine</string>
    <string name="title_activity_view_wish_wine">Wine</string>
    <string name="button_more_information">More Information</string>
    <string name="button_home">Home</string>
    <string name="button_education">Education</string>
    <string name="title_activity_types">Types</string>
    <string name="Learning">Learning</string>
    <string name="title_activity_learn">Learn</string>
    <string name="types_info">\tWhen it comes to wine, there are 5 main categories - Red, White, Rose, Fortified Wine, and Sparkling Wine. The catergorizing of wines comes from their difference in production methods which results in defferent taste and texture. Red wine has a slight bitterness to it because it is fermented with its skin on, resulting in the red color. White wine is sweeter because it is fermented without its skin, resulting in a light gold color. Rose is in between red wine and white wine because it is left for a period of time with its skin, but the skin is then removed after a certain time. Sparkling wine\'s sparkle comes from its fermentation, which usually occurs in a bottle, a large tank, or from injection. The carbon dioxide adds a slight amount of bitterness to it, but the sweetness of the white or rose wine covers it up. Fortified wines, like port, are wines which have other alcohols added to them. They usually have a higher alcohol content, and therefore less sweetness, coming with more of a kick.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_history">History</string>
    <string name="history_info">\tWine has been around since 7000BC. Wine is commonly believed to have started in Georgia; however, it wasn\'t until the Roman Empire that wine really became popular. Wine started off with limited production, and was served only to the nobles. The first sign of mass production was found in Armenia by what historians believe to be the oldest winery. Although most wines (both historically and currently) are made of grapes, the Chinese were known to make wine out of rice. \n\tThere are many stories behind how wine was first discovered. One of the more popular stories of the origin of wine is that of King Jamshid banishing one of his harem ladies from his kingdom. Feeling sad, she considered suicide, and found her way into the king\'s warehouse in search for poison. There she found a jar marked poison containing the remnants of grapes that had spoiled and been deemed undrinkable. Little did she know that the \"poison\" was actually fermented grapes. After drinking it, she discovered the effect to be pleasant and her spirits were lifted. She took her discovery to the king, who fell in love with the wine, and accepted the girl back into his harem. </string>
    <string name="title_activity_regions">Regions</string>
    <string name="regions_info">\tA wine region is a region that is recognized to be an area major wine production. Areas with vineyards can apply to have their location be labeled as a wine region, but must be approved. A location that is a wine region is not considered to be \"better\" than a location that does not have the label, but it is more prestigious to be producing wine within a wine region.\n\tWine Regions are mainly catogerized into two categories - Old World and New World. The Old World title is given to the countries that have been in the winemaking industry for centuries, such as Italy, Spain, and France, while the New World title is given to the countries that are newer to the wine making business, such as the USA and Mexico. Old World and New World tells nothing of the quality of the wine but from the difference in winemaking techniques, there are certain expectations from each of the regions. The five largest wine producing countries are China, USA, Italy, France and Spain. Within each wine region, there are usually smaller wine regions associated with it. For example, the USA is a wine region, and within the USA, California is a wine region. Within California, Nappa Valley is also a wine region. Each of these areas is considered a wine region.</string>
    <string name="title_activity_production">Production</string>
    <string name="production_info">\tWine production is also known as winemaking, or vinification. Although wines are predominantly made of grapes, there are also wines made from honey, like Mead. There are a multitude of ways of producing wine. \n\tRed wine is made from red grapes. The red grapes are juiced and left to ferment with yeast. The skins of the grapes are left to ferment with it, giving it its red color and bitter taste. Red wines are usually left to ferment in oak barrels for 1-2 years before being placed into bottles for distribution. \n\tWhite wines, on the other hand, are made of both white and red grapes. They are juiced and left to ferment without their skins on, resulting in their light golden color. They are usually left to ferment for 1 year before being bottled for distribution.\n\tRose is a mixture of the red and white methods. Rose is made from red grapes. They are juiced and left to ferment with their skins, but their skins are removed early on, giving the wine a more pinkish color. Rose wines are typically left for 1 year before being bottled and sent for distribution.</string>
    <string name="button_quiz">Quiz</string>
    <string name="Quiz">Quiz</string>
    <string name="education_text">Education</string>
    <string name="title_activity_quiz">Quiz</string>
    <string name="title_activity_etiquette">Etiquette</string>
    <string name="etiquette_info"> \tThere are two main categories to Wine Etiquette - temperature and serving. It is very important to follow the correct etiquette when wine is involved because it can drastically change the experience of the wine.\n\tTemperature - Different wines are best served at different temperatures as temperature can affect the taste of the wine. For example, white wines are usually chilled before drinking to concentrate the sweetness of the wine, while red wines are usually drunk at room temperature to allow the drinker to experience it\'s complexity in flavor. \n\nSparkling\t\t42-54 fahrenheit\t\t6-10 celcius\nRose\t\t\t\t48-54 fahrenheit\t\t9-12 celcius\nWhite\t\t\t\t48-58 fahrenheit\t\t9-14 celcius\nSherry(light)\t48-58 fahrenheit\t\t9-14 celcius\nRed\t\t\t\t\t57-68 fahrenheit\t\t13-20 celcius\nFortified\t\t\t57-68 fahrenheit\t\t13-20 celcius\nSherry(dark)\t57-68 fahrenheir\t\t13-20 celcius\n\n\tThe serving of wine is also a big part of the wine tasting experience. Red wine and Sherry (dark) wine are usually uncorked an hour early to allow the wine to air (oxidize) while sparkling, rose, white, and fortified wines are usually uncorked at time of drinking. Some wines are poured into a decanted bottle (a glass bottle with a large mouth, and even larger body) which is designed to help the wine air. Choosing the wine glass is also an important part of the preperation. Wines that need airing usually go well in a wine glass with a really large mouth and body - a pear shaped glass - to allow the wines to air, while white wines and sparkling wines go better with slim glasses to allow the wine to maintain it\'s cool temperature or keep it\'s bubbles. \n\tAfter the preparation, pouring wine is also very important as red wines are usually poured down the middle of the glass to circulate the wine while the carbonated wines are poured along the sides of the glass to keep prevent splashing and protect it\'s bubbles.</string>
    <string name="learn_text">Learn</string>
    <string name="title_activity_etiquette_learn">Etiquette</string>
    <string name="title_activity_history_learn">History</string>
    <string name="title_activity_production_learn">Production</string>
    <string name="title_activity_regions_learn">Regions</string>
    <string name="title_activity_types_learn">Types</string>
    <string name="title_activity_food_pairings_learn">Food Pairings</string>
    <string name="foodpairings_info">\tWine and food pairing have always been a very important aspect of enjoying wine. Wine can enhance certain foods\' flavors and vice versa. The idea is similar to drinking a very sour lemonade, and then drinking a sweet orange juice - the sour lemonade makes the sweet orange juice sweeter. \n\tFor ages, people have been experimenting with wine and food to find good pairings. Many fine restaurants recommend wines that go well with the food ordered to enhance the dining experience. Unlike other aspects of wine, wine pairing is relative. There are certain conventions when it comes to good food and wine pairings, but it is completely personal. When unsure, the conventions are good to fall back on, but finding your own set of wine and food pairing is much more important, and also much more fun.</string>
    <string name="button_pairings_list">Pairings List</string>
    <string name="title_activity_regions_quiz">Regions Quiz</string>
    <string name="title_activity_etiquette_quiz">Etiquette Quiz</string>
    <string name="title_activity_add_wine">Add Wine</string>
    <string name="title_activity_history_quiz">History Quiz</string>
    <string name="title_activity_production_quiz">Production Quiz</string>
    <string name="title_activity_user_stats">User Stats</string>
    <string name="userStats">User Stats</string>

</resources>